Elier Hernandez

Full Stack Web Developer currently located in Miami, Florida. My interest in the web started back in 2018 as a designer when I started creating user interfaces and experiences for the web. I learned development in order to bring my designs to life, and fell in love with it. Now I dedicate myself full time to web development, it's one of my great passions.

Miami Gardens, FL (786) 478-5402

Email: elierporto@gmail.com
Website: elierhernandez
Linkedin: in/elier-hernandez

EXPERIENCE

Independent Developer — Full Stack Web Developer

OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

Pencils & Inks (Project)

- E-commerce website developed from scratch using React & Next js for the client side and Ruby on Rails for the server APIs.
- The website includes various features such as; products, users, filter settings, a review system with ratings, a shopping cart, and an admin panel for CRUD operations.

Webmarks (Project)

- Online file system that allows users to store folders and urls on the web.
- The front end for this application was built using React and Material UI.
- The back end API was built using Node with Express, and the user authentication was handled with Passport.

Skyline Media Marketing Website (Client Project)

- Skyline is an advertisement agency located in New York. I worked with them for 2 years and developed their main website using React and Gatsby.
- They experienced a 100%+ increase in leads from their marketing campaigns.

Skyline Media Marketing — Graphic & Web Designer

MARCH 2018 - APRIL 2020

Responsible for the development of customer-facing websites and graphic design used for marketing campaigns. Worked as a team with other designers and marketers to ensure the best results for our clients.

- Built client websites using HTML, CSS, Javascript, React and Wordpress.
- Helped agency clients build a strong online web presence.
- Designed logos, business cards and user interfaces for clients.
- Designed graphics to increase Facebook Marketing conversions by 30%+

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Html, Css, Sass, Javascript, React, Typescript, Redux, Next, Gatsby, Node, Express, Ruby, Ruby on Rails

Design

Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator

EDUCATION

Miami Dade College

2011 - 2013 @ Miami, FL Pursued bachelor of arts and completed core college courses for 2 years.

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

2020 - 2021 @ Udemy

Learned the fundamentals of web development including; html, css, js, node, http protocol, & sql databases.

Modern React Bootcamp

2021 @ Udemy

Learned the fundamentals of react components, state management, lifecycle methods and hooks.

LANGUAGES

English, Spanish